Let’s try your first program in Python. A statement or expression is an instruction
the computer will run or execute. Perhaps the simplest program you can write
is a print statement. When you run the print statement, Python will
simply display the value in the parentheses. The value in the parentheses is called the
argument. If you are using a Jupiter notebook in this
course, you will see a small rectangle with the statement.
This is called a cell. If you select this cell with your mouse, then
click the run cell button. The statement will execute. The result will be displayed beneath
the cell. We will follow this paradigm in the videos.
It’s customary to comment your code. This tells other people what your code does. You
simply put a hash symbol proceeding your comment. When you run the code, Python will ignore
the comment. A Syntactic error is when Python does not
understand your code. For example, if you spell print "frint", you will get an error
message. A Semantic error is when your logic is wrong.
For example, if you enter Python 102 instead of Python 101, you don't get an error message,
but your code is wrong.